The choice will be clear.
Live Free or Die Hard is a action, thriller film directed by Len Wiseman.
John McClane is back and badder than ever, and this time he calls on the services of a young hacker in his bid to
stop a ring of Internet terrorists intent on taking control of America's computer infrastructure.
John McClane, played by Bruce Willis.
Thomas Gabriel, played by Timothy Olyphant.
Matt Farrell, played by Justin Long.
Deputy Director Miguel Bowman, played by Cliff Curtis.
Lucy McClane, played by Mary Elizabeth Winstead.
Trey, played by Jonathan Sadowski.
Live Free or Die Hard (released as Die Hard 4.0 outside North America) is a
2007 American action thriller film directed by Len Wiseman.
It is the sequel to Die Hard with a Vengeance (1995) and the
fourth installment in the Die Hard film series.
It is based on the 1997 article "A Farewell to Arms"
written for Wired magazine by John Carlin.
The film's name references New Hampshire's state motto, "Live Free or Die".
In the film, NYPD Detective John McClane (Bruce Willis) attempts to stop a cyber-terrorist, Thomas Gabriel (Timothy Olyphant) who hacks into government and commercial
computers across the United States with the goal of starting a "fire sale" cyber attack that would disable key elements of the nation's infrastructure.
Justin Long, Cliff Curtis, Maggie Q, Mary Elizabeth
Winstead and Kevin Smith also star.
Live Free or Die Hard was released in the United States
on June 27, 2007 by 20th Century Fox.
The film grossed $388 million worldwide, making it the
highest-grossing installment in the Die Hard series.
It received positive reviews from critics.
It is the only Die Hard film to be theatrically released with a PG-13 rating from the MPAA,
although an unrated edition would later be made available on home media.
A fifth film, A Good Day to Die Hard, was released in 2013.
The film explores themes of helicopter, washington
dc, usa, hostage, detective, fbi.
The tone is intense.